 const data=[
    {
        id: 1,
        question:"Who is the father of Computers?",
        option1:"james Gosling",
        option2:"Charles Babbage",
        option3:"Dennis Ritchie",
        option4:"Bjarne Stroustrup",
        ans:2,
    },
    {
        id: 2,
        question:"Which of the following is the correct abbreviation of COMPUTER?",
        option1:"Commonly Occupied Machines Used in Technical and Educational Research",
        option2:"Commonly Operated Machines Used in Technical and Enrollment Research",
        option3:"Commonly Oriented Machines Used in Technical and Educational Research",
        option4:" Commonly Operated Machines Used in Technical and Educational Research",
        ans:4,
    },
    {
        id: 3,
        question:"Which of the following computer language is written in binary codes only?",
        option1:"pascal",
        option2:"machine language",
        option3:"C",
        option4:"C#",
        ans:2,
    },
    {
        id: 4,
        question:"which of the following is brain of computer?",
        option1:"central processing unit",
        option2:"Memory",
        option3:"Arthimetic and logic unit",
        option4:"control unit",
        ans:1,
    },
    {
        id: 5,
        question:"Which of the folowing is not characteristic of a computer?",
        option1:"versatility",
        option2:"Accuracy",
        option3:"Dilligence",
        option4:"I.Q",
        ans:4,
    },
    {
        id: 6,
        question:"Which of the following is the correct definition of Computer?",
        option1:"Computer is a machine or device that can be programmed to perform arithmetical or logic operation sequences automatically",
        option2:"Computer understands only binary language which is written in the form of 0s & 1s",
        option3:"Computer is a programmable electronic device that stores, retrieves, and processes the data",
        option4:"All of the mentioned",
        ans:4,
    },
    {
        id: 7,
        question:"Which of the following language does the computer understand?",
        option1:"Computer understands only C Language",
        option2:" Computer understands only Assembly Language",
        option3:"Computer understands only Binary Language",
        option4:"Computer understands only BASIC",
        ans:3,
    },
    {
        id: 8,
        question:"Which of the following is designed to control the operations of a computer?",
        option1:"User",
        option2:"Application Software",
        option3:"System Software",
        option4:"Utility Software",
        ans:3,
    },
    {
        id: 9,
        question:"Who discovered world wide web?",
        option1:"james Gosling",
        option2:"Tim Berners Lee",
        option3:"Dennis Ritchie",
        option4:"Bjarne Stroustrup",
        ans:2,
    },
    {
        id: 10,
        question:" Which of the following part of a processor contains the hardware necessary to perform all the operations required by a computer?",
        option1:"Controller",
        option2:"Registers",
        option3:"Cache",
        option4:"Data path",
        ans:4,
    }

];
export default data;